Order of Railway Conductors and Brakemen and Seaboard Airline Railroad Company General Committee of Adjustment Files 5754
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Order of Railway Conductors and Brakemen and Seaboard Airline Railroad Company General Committee of Adjustment Files
1921-1977
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Order of Railway Conductors and Brakemen(ORC&B
Seaboard Air Line Railway Company (SAL)
5754
5 cubic feet
5 linear ft.
Records (documents).
3126697
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, January 27, 2015
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 02, 2019
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5148: Order of Railway Conductors and Brakemen Records
Railroads -- United States -- Employees -- Sources; Railroads -- Employees -- Labor unions -- United States -- Sources; Order of Railway Conductors and Brakemen; Seaboard Air Line Railway Company
3126697
- Misc. Correspondence and Claims (Box 1)
  - General Committee of Adjustment - Nomination and Election of Vice General Chairman and Secretary, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen Strike - Seaboard Air Line Railroad Company, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Scope and Contents
    March31, 1966
  - Correspondence and Miscellaneous Regarding the "G.I. Bill" and Veterans, 1942-1966 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - United Transportation Union General Communication Regarding Proposed By-Laws, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - General Chairman's Salary, 1926-1972 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Per Diem and Expense Allowance - General Committee and Divisions, 1942-1973 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Expense Away from Home - General Chairman, 1964-1969 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Election of Secretary, General Committee of Adjustment, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Election of Secretary of the General Committee "C", 1974 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Sub-Committee New Settlement Lakeland-Ocala; Also Southland Settlement and Light Engine Movement Between Saint Petersburg and Albany, 1940-1943 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - General Committee Meeting, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Meeting of Sub-Central Committee, 1948-1951 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Sub-General Committee Meeting, Wilmington, North Carolina, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    November 9-10, 1952.
  - General Committee Meeting, Jacksonville, Florida, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    January 19-20, 1953. Found Empty December 9, 2014.
  - Meetings of the Joint Sub General Committee Meeting in Rocky Mount, North Carolina, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    April 24, 1956
  - General Committee Meeting - Rocky Mount, North Carolina, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    January 21, 1957
  - Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen - General Committee Meeting Minutes, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - General Committee - Jacksonville, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    January 1968
  - General Committee of Adjustment Meeting in Jacksonville, Florida - Elect Officers Due to Resignation of General Chairman T.L. McCollister, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    January 14, 1970
  - General Committee Meeting, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    January 1971
  - Minutes of All General Committee Meetings, 1942-1954 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Grand Division Convention Held in Miami, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    June 16, 1958
  - Instructions to Local Secretaries, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Proposal to Move International Headquarters to Hot Springs, Arkansas, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Conductors Annual Meeting, 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Service Emblems, 1942-1953 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Members of the General Committee Being Held Out of Service to Assist the General Chairman Roster of Members Paying Dues to GE-850, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Appeals of Merger, 1926-1935 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Claim for Through Freight Instead of Passenger Case of D.W. Hall, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    august 1, 1962
  - Claim of Brother J.O. Brooker - Account Performing Fireman's Duties, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    December 7, 1964
  - Claim of Brother S.H. Walker for One Day Instead of 30 Minutes at Port Boca Grande, Florida (Pending), 1964 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    April 19, 1964
  - Claim of Brother C.B. Gibbons for One Day Instead of Miles Account Lap Back Armston to C. Water (Pending), 1964 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    January 18, 1964
  - C.K. Moriarty Case - Claim for Two Day Passenger, 423 Miles, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    Original Case: January 29-30 1963; Sent to Labor board September 20, 1963
  - E.E. Scoggins Case - Claim for Time Lost 10 Days, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    August 31, 1963
  - Case History of Brother J.C. Miller - Sickness as Handled, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Central Trades and Labor Assembly of Tampa, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Insurance, 1931-1940 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Travelers Insurance Agreement - Circulars from the Grand Division, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    April 1, 1964
  - Hartford Life Insurance Company - Group Insurance Enrollment Cards, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Group Hospital and Insurance Forms, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - United States Railroad Retirement Board, 1940-1968 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - President's Membership Committee Letters - Order of Railway Conductors and Brakemen, 1964-1967 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Letters to and From C.H. Anderson, General Secretary-Treasurer of the Order of Railway Conductors and Brakemen, 1962-1970 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Cases, Awards, and Appeals (Box 2)
  - Correspondence with Seaboard Air Line Company, 1963-1967 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence with Seaboard Coast Line Railroad Company, 1964-1968 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence with S.M. Duffer, Director of Personnel, Seaboard Air Line Railroad Company, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - National Railroad Adjustment Board, 1948-1949 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Investigation and Discipline of Conductor V.B. Horton Regarding His Position During an Emergency, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Investigation Regarding the Collision of Train 22, Engine 3014, and the Second Ocala Switcher, Engine 1606 in the Yard Lead at Ocala, Florida, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Accident took place March 12, 1964
  - Correspondence regarding Order of Railway Conductors and brakemen Case Number 249-66 (Deadhead Conductor, J.P. Brown), 1967 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous Claims, 1947-1958 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence Regarding Conference in Florida, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Conference Scheduled for February 12, 1964
  - Award 21296, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Award 21297, 1955-1964 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Award 21298, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Award 21300, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Award 21303, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Award 21305, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Award 21307, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Award 21312, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Award 21313, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Award 21314, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Award 21342, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Award 21441, 1953-1955 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Award 21442, 1943-1951 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Lay-Over - Changing (Home Terminals, Etcetera), 1942-1947 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    Includes Cases and Appeals
- Project 70's Correspondence (United Transportation Union - Seaboard Coast Line), 1977 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Project 70's Correspondence (United Transportation Union International-United Transportation Union C and Local Committee), 1975-1977 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Project 70's Correspondence (Seaboard Coast Line - United Transportation Union T), 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Project 70's Correspondence (Seaboard Coast Line - United Transportation Union E), 1977 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  Wednesday, February 16 1977
- Jacksonville, Florida - Project 70`s (L. Parrish), 1977 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  Wednesday, February 16, 1977. Found empty December 9, 2014, but with notes along the extent of the folder.
- Jacksonville, Florida - Project 70's (F.L. Oglesby), 1977 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  Wednesday, February 16, 1977. Notes along exterior of folder
- Jacksonville, Florida - Project 70's (C.E. Vause), 1977 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  Wednesday, February 16, 1977
- Tampa, Florida - Project 70's (B.G. Caruthers), 1977 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  Tuesday, February 22, 1977
- Tampa, Florida - Project 70's (C.M. Darby), 1977 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Jacksonville, Florida and Tampa, Florida (T.C. Parker), 1977 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  Wednesday, February 16 and Tuesday, February 22, 1977
- Jacksonville, Florida and Tampa, Florida (Marvin Jordan), 1977 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Project 70's Meeting, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  March 25, 1974
- Project 70's, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Savannah, Georgia - Project 70's (J.O. Garrett), 1977 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  Tuesday, February 8, 1977
- Savannah, Georgia - Project 70's (J.S. Colson), 1977 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Florence, South Carolina and Savannah, Georgia - Project 70's (W.F. Southwell), 1977 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  Thursday, January 27 and Tuesday, February 8, 1977
- Rocky Mount, North Carolina - Project 70's (C.H. Briley), 1977 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  Wednesday, February 2, 1977
- Rocky Mount, North Carolina - Project 70's (P.D. Bland), 1977 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Rocky Mount, North Carolina - Project 70's (E.B. Orebaugh), 1977 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Raleigh, North Carolina and Rocky Mount, North Carolina- Project 70's (R.W. Lewis), 1977 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  Tuesday, February 1 and Wednesday, February 2, 1977
- Raleigh, North Carolina - Project 70's (P.B. Arbogast), 1977 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  Tuesday, February 1, 1977
- Raleigh, North Carolina - Project 70's (W.W. Gunter), 1977 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Waycross, Georgia - Project 70's (W.C. Wingard), 1977 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  Wednesday, February 9, 1977
- Waycross, Georgia - Project 70's (C.W. Taylor), 1977 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Waycross, Georgia - Project 70's (W.C. Oxford), 1977 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Atlanta, Georgia - Project 70's (S.W. Turner), 1977 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  Wednesday, January 19, 1977
- Atlanta, Georgia - Project 70's (R.N. McNeely), 1977 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Atlanta, Georgia - Project 70's (W.N. Abell), 1977 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Atlanta, Georgia - Project 70's (T.M. Vaughn), 1977 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Florence, South Carolina - Project 70's (W.W. Luckey), 1977 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  Thursday, January 27, 1977
- Florence, South Carolina - Project 70's (H.S. Waddell), 1977 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Salary of Committee Officers, Employees, and Office Secretary, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Salaries of the Order of Railway Conductors and Brakemen; Request for Increases, 1957-1969 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Consolidation of General Committee, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Supplemental Pension for Full-Time Employees of the General Committee, 1970-1972 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Agreement Consolidating United Transportation Union, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  June 1, 1969
- Consolidating General Committee - E and C (Atlantic Coast Lines) and C (Piedmont and Northern), 1970-1972 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  Includes Ballots
- Ballots - Vice General Chairman, Conductors, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Southern Association, 1969-1974 (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Conductor's General Committee Meetings, 1921-1942 (Box 3, Folder 40)
- Nomination and Election of Officers on Atlantic Coast Line, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 41)
- Conductors General Committee Meetings - Regular and Special Session, 1945-1954 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  1945, 1946, 1952, 1954
- Atlantic Coast Line System Federation - Withdrawn, 1938-1970 (Box 3, Folder 43)
- Acquisitions by the Atlantic Coast Line, 1943-1952 (Box 3, Folder 44)
- General Grievance Committee, 1948-1950 (Box 3, Folder 45)
- Correspondence Regarding Committee Dates, 1950-1961 (Box 3, Folder 46)
- Claims to be discussed at conferences, 1951-1966 (Box 3, Folder 47)
- Homer Knizley Investigation, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 48)
- General Committee Activities Report, 1943-1954 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- GC Activities Reports 1943-54 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Committee Pay Hospital Insurance, GC (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Committee Pay Hospital Insurance - General Committee, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Are passenger crews that are assigned to run paying mileage in excess of their guarantee entitled to the mileage of their assignment?, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  July 1936
- Overtime Claim (Burney) and Overtime Agreement Clause (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Seaboard Air Line Railway Company and Overtime Claims (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Seaboard Air Line Railway (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Order of Railway Conductors and Brakemen (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Seaboard Air Line Railroad and Order of Railway Conductors and Brakemen Dispute (Box 4, Folder 7)
- General Arbitration/Disputes (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Seaboard Air Line Railroad Company: Contract Article II (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Deadheading - Article 12 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Article 13 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Article 15 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Qualifications for Passenger Service (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Article 18 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Article 22 - Freight Service (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Article 23 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Article 25 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Article 26 - General (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Qualifying for Article 26(h) (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Article 26 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Article 26(D)(8) (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Seniority (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Assigning Jr. Extra Conductor to Assignment When No Bids Received - What he May do to Get Away from Assignment When Jr. Men put Up (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Vacancies (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Pool Freight (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Mileage Limitation (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Mileage Limitation Part 2 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Project 70 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Article 13 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Railway Labor Act and Worker Agreements (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Freight Conductors Examination Pertaining to Promotion Sal (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Letters to and From the President of the ORC&B (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Letters from Bro. T.C.> Bolin, General Chairman ORC&B - Sal (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Willard W. Carson, Senior V.P., PO Box 4011 Cedar Rapids, Iowa 52407 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- M. Paul R. Bennett, General Chair (ACL); PO Box 642 Lakeland, Florida 33801 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- J.L. Summers, Jr. (BLF&E) Florida State Legislature Representative; 4748 Ramona Blvd. Jacksonville, Florida 32205 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Clifford H. Rex (VP); 505 Wilderness Road Louisville, Kentucky 40214 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- C.H. Anderson (General Secretary and Treasurer) (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Order of Railway Conductors (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Payrolls (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Railway Retirement Board (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Sinking Funds (Box 5, Folder 15)
- General Committee Expenses (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Cypress Garden Produce, Inc. Strike (Box 5, Folder 17)
- General Funds (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Salaries (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Investigation Rule - Employees Right to Representative (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Joint General Chairman (Box 5, Folder 21)
- General Chairman Vacation (Box 5, Folder 22)
- General Committee of Adjustment (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Cooperative Committee Proposal (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Division Cards (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Carriers (Box 5, Folder 26)
- Minutes of General Committee Meeting at Tampa, Florida (1/12-13/71) (Box 5, Folder 27)
- General Committee of Adjustment (Box 5, Folder 28)
- SAL General Committee of Adjustment (Box 5, Folder 29)
- General Committee of Adjustment (Box 5, Folder 30)
- List of Seaboard Employees - Jacksonville, FL (Box 5, Folder 31)
- ORC&B Quarterly Member Reports (Box 5, Folder 32)
- Appeal Cases to General Committee - Norfolk, VA - 2/14/1938 (Box 5, Folder 33)
- PR Bennett (Box 5, Folder 34)
- General Instructions (Box 5, Folder 35)
- General Chairman Elections (Box 5, Folder 36)
- Appeals to Settlements (Box 5, Folder 37)
- Rate of Pay for Conductors and Trainmen (Box 5, Folder 38)
- Election of Vice General Chairman (Box 5, Folder 39)
- Sinking Funds Assessment (Box 5, Folder 40)
- Financial Standing - General Committee Bank Deposits from the Grand Lodge (Box 5, Folder 41)